Akseli Tuominen

Viides Linja 16 A 24 • Helsinki, 00530 • akseli.tuominen@aalto.fi • 0449800067• LinkedIn, GitHub

Profile



I am a third-year student from Aalto university. My strengths include promptness, self-discipline, curiosity and communication. I excel in analytical thinking, programming, teamwork and mathematical problems. Proof of my strengths include my good success in university including a good GPA and a scholarship. From this workplace, I want to gather as much experience in the field as possible and learn as much as possible. My goal is to hone my skills needed in this field of work and advance in my personal career.

Helsinki

Education

Aalto University	Helsinki
Bachelor of Electrical engineering, Automation and System engineering, GPA 4.03	28.05.2024
Finnish reserve office school Class 257	Hamina 2021
Kauniainen High school	Kauniainen
Scholarships from chemistry and organizing events	30.05.2020

Experience

Ge Healthcare 30.05.2022 - Present Manufacturing engineer, calibration intern

- I worked as a calibration intern in a team that supported production.
- Worked with many different devices and equipment.
- Learned a lot about varying hardware and software and enhanced my co-operation skills.
- I got used to working as an engineer and learned about widely used production methods like Lean.

Confide Helsinki 07.2019-09.2021 **Lobby attendant**

- Worked in the lobby of an office building.
- Learned to work, co-operate and solve problems with corporate contacts.

Confide

Office Assistant 07.2019-09.2020

• Worked as an office assistant in Fortum's headquarters for multiple summers and did some smaller jobs seldom.

• Learned what it is like to work in an office and improved my teamwork capabilities tremendously.

Skills & Interests

Technical: Great computer skills with Windows, Linux and MacOS

Programming: React, Node.js, C, C++, Scala, Python, PLC languages, Java, Java-Script and SQL

Projects: Most personal projects found in GitHub. Including Full stack, scripts and games.

Language: Fluent Finnish, Fluent English and Proficient Swedish

Certifications: SFS 6002 valid electrical safety card and a certificate for taking a full stack programming course.

Interests: Tennis, programming and playing guitar